<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog</id>
    <title>LinkWell Nodes Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>LinkWell Nodes Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Find a Chainlink Oracle: A Guide for Web3 Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/How-To-Find-A-Chainlink-Oracle</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/How-To-Find-A-Chainlink-Oracle"/>
        <updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where to find a Chainlink node operator, oracle address, and job ID for incorporating real-world data into your Web3 application.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="where-to-find-a-chainlink-node-operator-oracle-address-and-job-id-for-incorporating-real-world-data-into-your-web3-application">Where to find a Chainlink node operator, oracle address, and job ID for incorporating real-world data into your Web3 application<a href="#where-to-find-a-chainlink-node-operator-oracle-address-and-job-id-for-incorporating-real-world-data-into-your-web3-application" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Where to find a Chainlink node operator, oracle address, and job ID for incorporating real-world data into your Web3 application" title="Direct link to Where to find a Chainlink node operator, oracle address, and job ID for incorporating real-world data into your Web3 application">​</a></h2><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/chainlink-oracle/Chainlink_Node_Operator.webp" alt="What is a Chainlink Node Operator" class="img_ev3q"></p><p align="center">Source: https://blog.chain.link/what-is-a-chainlink-node-operator</p><p>Developers building Web3 applications are faced with a series of challenging hurdles — selecting the appropriate blockchain, maximizing their security, and integrating with off-chain data using oracle platforms like Chainlink.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Looking for a Chainlink oracle address or job id?</strong> View our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink data feeds documentation</a>, which has everything you need to get started requesting data.</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Chainlink Oracle Addresses and Job IDs | LinkWell Nodes</strong><em>Chainlink oracle addresses and Job IDs to connect your smart contract to any API on the internet. Retrieve RWA prices…</em>docs.linkwellnodes.io</a></p><p>At LinkWell Nodes, we understand that staying updated on Chainlink’s services can be a challenge in its own right, let alone the task of finding and collaborating with a Chainlink node operator. In this article, we aim to use our extensive experience running Chainlink oracles to clarify these issues.</p><p>In this article we will cover:</p><ol><li><p>Why Chainlink?</p></li><li><p>What is a Chainlink oracle?</p></li><li><p>Why do I need a Chainlink oracle?</p></li><li><p><strong>Where to find a Chainlink oracle</strong></p></li><li><p>What to look for in a Chainlink oracle</p></li><li><p>Bonus: Chainlink’s vision for a decentralized compute marketplace</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="1-why-chainlink">1. Why Chainlink?<a href="#1-why-chainlink" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1. Why Chainlink?" title="Direct link to 1. Why Chainlink?">​</a></h2><p>Blockchain consensus mechanisms limit smart contracts from directly interacting with the internet, creating the blockchain <a href="https://chain.link/education-hub/oracle-problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">oracle problem</a>. This hurdle represents one of the greatest limitations to representing everyday contracts on the blockchain.</p><p>Hybrid smart contracts solve this by using oracles as middleware — enabling external data publishing &amp; retrieval, as well as scalable off-chain computations. Oracles act as a two-way bridge, enhancing connectivity while providing security against single points of failure (SPOFs).</p><p>Chainlink — the industry standard Web3 services platform — is the most widely used decentralized oracle network, securing over $21 billion in value (as of the time of this writing) across a diverse assortment of blockchains and use cases. It operates as an ecosystem with independent decentralized oracle networks, guaranteeing robust and versatile oracle services.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="2-what-is-a-chainlink-oracle-node-operator">2. What is a Chainlink Oracle (Node Operator)?<a href="#2-what-is-a-chainlink-oracle-node-operator" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2. What is a Chainlink Oracle (Node Operator)?" title="Direct link to 2. What is a Chainlink Oracle (Node Operator)?">​</a></h2><p>A <a href="https://blog.chain.link/what-is-a-chainlink-node-operator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink node operator</a> is a crucial part of the Chainlink network, tasked with the secure and reliable transfer of real-world data to blockchains. These operators manage <strong>Chainlink oracles</strong>, which effectively serve as bridges between external data sources (internet-based APIs), and blockchains. This crucial connection enables bi-directional communication between smart contracts and the outside world.</p><p>At the heart of this system is the Chainlink oracle — a runtime developed in Go by <a href="https://chainlinklabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Labs</a> and operated by independent node operator teams. Oracles form the backbone of decentralized oracle networks (DONs), which supply off-chain data and computational resources to support a wide range of Chainlink’s functionalities, including Data Feeds, Automation, VRF, and the Cross-Chain Interoperability Protocol (CCIP). The Chainlink network is an expandable ensemble of independent oracles. While the network is open to all for running an oracle, individual oracle networks can impose their own rules regarding participation and data management. Unlike typical blockchain environments, the Chainlink network does not employ a unified consensus mechanism, thereby allowing for greater flexibility and security among its networks.</p><p>While individual Chainlink oracles can directly handle requests (ie, using the <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Chainlink-Basic-Request-Model-Architectures" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Any API / basic request model</a>), they may also form decentralized oracle networks (DONs). These networks aggregate responses from multiple oracles and data sources, ultimately providing a highly secure, accurate, and reliable data feed.</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/chainlink-oracle/Chainlink_Oracle_Network.webp" alt="Decentralized Oracle Network Price Feed Example" class="img_ev3q"></p><p align="center">Source: https://chain.link/data-feeds</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="3-why-do-i-need-a-chainlink-oracle">3. Why do I need a Chainlink oracle?<a href="#3-why-do-i-need-a-chainlink-oracle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 3. Why do I need a Chainlink oracle?" title="Direct link to 3. Why do I need a Chainlink oracle?">​</a></h2><p>It would be natural to question at this point — if Chainlink oracles can offer their services via decentralized oracle networks, why would there be any need to interact with a single Chainlink oracle?</p><p>There are many reasons why interacting directly with a Chainlink node operator (oracle) can be extremely beneficial — or even necessary:</p><p><strong>1. Direct API Calls:</strong> Web3 developers can incorporate request logic within their smart contracts that execute API calls via a Chainlink oracle, allowing them to access data from any external data source on the internet. This process necessitates an <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">oracle address and a job id</a>, both of which are provided by a Chainlink node operator (see <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our documentation</a> for these).</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/chainlink-oracle/Chainlink_Basic_Request_Model.webp" alt="Using Chainlink's basic request model for Any API Integrations" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>2. Lower Costs:</strong> Working directly with a single Chainlink node operator can often be cheaper for your project than working with many. Speaking directly with your Chainlink node operator allows you to arrive at a price point that works for you. Some operators (such as ourselves) also provide discounts for high request volume, paying in advance, and alternative payment methods for certain Web3 startups.</p><p><strong>3. Unique Data/Price Feeds:</strong> Chainlink provides a diverse selection of <a href="https://data.chain.link/feeds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official data feeds</a>, encompassing various data types like asset prices, reserve balances, NFT floor prices, and more. While these data feeds cover a broad spectrum, Web3 developers often require data that goes beyond Chainlink’s existing official data feed offerings. To cater to these specialized needs, Chainlink node operators can create <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Build-A-Chainlink-Price-Feed-With-Flux-Aggregator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">custom price feeds</a> that can aggregate custom data such as low-cap asset prices, RWA (real-world asset) prices, stock prices, weather information, sports betting data, and proof-of-reserve information.</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/chainlink-oracle/Custom_Chainlink_Flux_Aggregator.webp" alt="Building custom Chainlink oracle price feeds with Flux Aggregator" class="img_ev3q"></p><blockquote><p>Chainlink node operators can easily assist in this endeavor, enabling Web3 developers to design and build their own decentralized oracle networks. These networks can be customized with specific update thresholds to aggregate data for virtually any use case.</p></blockquote><p><strong>4. Full-Service Support:</strong> Working directly with a node operator means a vastly-improved customer experience — especially for teams with limited technical expertise with blockchain oracles. A node operator can provide a <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/Development-Services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wide range of services</a>, including customer support, assistance integrating your smart contract, external adapter development, and monitoring / alerting you to potential issues.</p><p><strong>5. Reduced Technical Complexity:</strong> The intricacies of building Web3 apps can be daunting. An experienced node operator team can provide you with the necessary guidance and support needed to navigate complex issues and technical decisions in integrating your contract safely with your external data.</p><p><strong>6. Navigating Service Limitations:</strong> Every blockchain (and Chainlink service offering) has its own inherent limitations — from gas constraints to smart contract capabilities to payload sizes. A skilled Chainlink node operator can help you effectively overcome these challenges, by providing alternative options and bespoke customer solutions.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="4-where-to-find-a-chainlink-oracle">4. Where to Find a Chainlink Oracle<a href="#4-where-to-find-a-chainlink-oracle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 4. Where to Find a Chainlink Oracle" title="Direct link to 4. Where to Find a Chainlink Oracle">​</a></h2><p>While there is no centralized directory of Chainlink node operators, there are several methods we recommend for finding one:</p><ol><li><strong>Node Operator Websites:</strong> Visiting the websites of various Chainlink oracles can offer a comprehensive view of their services offerings and expertise. A quick Google search for “<strong>Chainlink oracle job ids</strong>” may yield several results.</li></ol><blockquote><p>LinkWell Nodes offers bespoke blockchain oracle services on all major EVM mainnet and testnet blockchains.
To view a directory of our oracle addresses and job IDs, please feel free to view our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink data feeds documentation</a>.</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Chainlink Oracle Addresses and Job IDs | LinkWell Nodes</strong><em>Chainlink oracle addresses and Job IDs to connect your smart contract to any API on the internet. Retrieve RWA prices…</em>docs.linkwellnodes.io</a></p><p>2.<strong>Chainlink Discord server:</strong> Engaging with the Chainlink community in Chainlink’s official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/chainlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a> is another great option for finding a Chainlink node operator who can serve your Web3 data needs.</p><p>3.<strong>Social Media:</strong> Many Chainlink oracles are active on social media channels such as <a href="https://twitter.com/LinkWell_Nodes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/80269483/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a>, and <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>.</p><p>4.<strong>Analytics Platforms:</strong> Various independent websites such as LinkPool’s Dune Analytics or Dextrac’s Prism application offer detailed information on the performance of the Chainlink Network, each decentralized oracle network, various node operators, and more.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="5-what-to-look-for-in-a-chainlink-oracle">5. What to Look For in a Chainlink Oracle<a href="#5-what-to-look-for-in-a-chainlink-oracle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 5. What to Look For in a Chainlink Oracle" title="Direct link to 5. What to Look For in a Chainlink Oracle">​</a></h2><p>Trust is fundamental when working with a single Chainlink node operator — especially given the critical role that external data plays in smart contracts.</p><p>Some of the key considerations to look for when finding a Chainlink node operator (oracle) are:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Reputation:</strong> In a decentralized environment, a node operator’s reputation for honesty and quality of service matters. Developers should choose Chainlink node operators with proven track records of excellent customer service.</p></li><li><p><strong>Reliability and Uptime:</strong> Reliable service is vital for applications needing real-time data, such as trading, lending, and DeFi insurance protocols. Look for a Chainlink node operator with a <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Service-Level-Agreement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">well-defined SLA</a> regarding their service and downtime.</p></li><li><p><strong>Security:</strong> Chainlink node operators manage sensitive data and may be the target of data breaches. Chainlink node operators should employ strong security measures to protect your data pipeline, and to prevent leaks that could jeopardize the blockchain ecosystem.</p></li><li><p><strong>Compliance and Legal Considerations:</strong> Trustworthy node operators should comply with legal and regulatory standards, critical in areas with strict data and privacy laws. This compliance prevents legal issues and ensures proper data handling.</p></li></ol><p>Some additional factors to consider are:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Effective Communication:</strong> Clear, transparent communication is essential for maintaining a seamless integration with Chainlink services, ultimately ensuring project success.</p></li><li><p><strong>Community Engagement:</strong> Do they have a history of supporting the Chainlink community, and working with other Web3 projects? If not, they may not be the most suitable to work with.</p></li><li><p><strong>Clear Processes and Documentation:</strong> We’ve all experienced the dread of poor documentation and/or processes when trying to navigate a new technology. An oracle with clear documentation can make all the difference.</p></li></ul><p>Working with a knowledgeable and competent Chainlink node operator can greatly streamline the process of requesting and building a custom data feed or Any API request pipeline, allowing you or your team to allocate resources more efficiently to your Web3 application. Furthermore, Chainlink node operators should ideally possess the expertise to assist in crafting your smart contract code, conducting code reviews, and suggesting gas optimization strategies within your smart contract. This not only saves time, but can also preserve valuable funds with each data request to the Chainlink oracle.</p><blockquote><p>At LinkWell Nodes, we pride ourselves in delivering a top-tier, transparent, full-service customer experience.
<strong>Have a question about your Web3 project?</strong> Join our <a href="https://discord.gg/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a> for the fastest assistance.</p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="6-bonus-chainlinks-vision-for-a-decentralized-compute-marketplace"><strong>6. Bonus: Chainlink’s Vision For a Decentralized Compute Marketplace</strong><a href="#6-bonus-chainlinks-vision-for-a-decentralized-compute-marketplace" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 6-bonus-chainlinks-vision-for-a-decentralized-compute-marketplace" title="Direct link to 6-bonus-chainlinks-vision-for-a-decentralized-compute-marketplace">​</a></h2><p>At the 2023 SmartCon, Sergey Nazarov shared his vision for Chainlink to develop a <strong>Decentralized Compute Marketplace</strong> (DCM). This marketplace would enable users to allocate a security budget and obtain data, computation, and security services based on that budget. Such a development would make it easier for developers to establish custom DONs in order to integrate with Chainlink’s comprehensive suite of Web3 services.</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/chainlink-oracle/Chainlink_Decentralized_Compute_Marketplace.webp" alt="Chainlink_Decentralized_Compute_Marketplace" class="img_ev3q"></p><p align="center">Source: https://blog.chain.link/platform-for-verifiable-web/#a_manipulation-resistant_world_built_on_the_verifiable_web</p><p>Although the specifics of how the DCM will function remain uncertain, it seems likely that developers will have the option to choose not only the number of Chainlink oracles to service their DON, but also select <em>which</em> Chainlink oracles are part of the DON. Should Chainlink adopt this approach for the DCM, it will be important to understand the detailed metrics and information about each Chainlink node operator — as explored in this article.</p><center><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G8uWGzXHueo" frameborder="0"></iframe></center><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2><p>The journey to finding a suitable Chainlink oracle involves many challenges, including understanding the Chainlink ecosystem as a whole, and finding a Chainlink node operator that works for you.</p><p>Understanding your project’s specific needs, exploring various sources for potential candidates, and evaluating them based on performance metrics and other criteria, are some of the key challenges faced when finding a node operator.</p><p>The right operator will not only ensure the seamless integration of external data within your smart contract, but also save you time (and money), thereby contributing to the overall success of your Web3 project.</p><blockquote><p>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink community oracle, providing custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions across virtually all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.
Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a>, or hop into the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkWell Nodes Discord server</a> and ask for help!
Disclaimer: all views and opinions expressed in this article are strictly our own.</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" src="/assets/images/lw-banner_1080x606-c6d84e1ae6e43af8c26ee04d238969be.webp" title="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" width="1080" height="606" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="chainlink oracle" term="chainlink oracle"/>
        <category label="smart contracts" term="smart contracts"/>
        <category label="price feed" term="price feed"/>
        <category label="web3" term="web3"/>
        <category label="blockchain" term="blockchain"/>
        <category label="node operator" term="node operator"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chainlink Price Feeds: Connect your Web3 App to a Custom Flux Monitor DON]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Build-A-Chainlink-Price-Feed-With-Flux-Aggregator</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Build-A-Chainlink-Price-Feed-With-Flux-Aggregator"/>
        <updated>2024-03-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to build and integrate a custom Chainlink oracle price feed using FluxAggregator for aggregating real-world data on-chain for your Web3 application.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="a-how-to-guide-for-building-a-custom-chainlink-oracle-price-feed-that-can-be-integrated-into-your-web3-application">A how-to guide for building a custom Chainlink oracle price feed that can be integrated into your Web3 application.<a href="#a-how-to-guide-for-building-a-custom-chainlink-oracle-price-feed-that-can-be-integrated-into-your-web3-application" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A how-to guide for building a custom Chainlink oracle price feed that can be integrated into your Web3 application." title="Direct link to A how-to guide for building a custom Chainlink oracle price feed that can be integrated into your Web3 application.">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Chainlink Blog- How Price Feeds Secure DeFi" src="/assets/images/Header-57a164fd9fbd6912c37809360315531e.webp" title="Chainlink Blog- How Price Feeds Secure DeFi" width="2048" height="791" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Smart contracts that opt out of Chainlink services such as price feeds resemble computers without internet access - highly restricted in capability.</p><p>Many Web3 developers are completely unaware that they can build and integrate any Chainlink price feed into their Web3 application that they need. Chainlink provides a diverse selection of <a href="https://data.chain.link/feeds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official data feeds</a>, encompassing various data types like asset prices, reserve balances, NFT floor prices, and more. While these feeds cover a broad spectrum, Web3 developers sometimes require data that goes beyond Chainlink's existing data feed offerings. To cater to these specialized needs, Chainlink allows for the creation of custom price feeds.</p><p>In this article we will:</p><ol><li><p>Explain how decentralized Chainlink price feeds work.</p></li><li><p>Define high-level steps for creating a price feed for your Web3 application.</p></li><li><p>Offer a comparison between Chainlink <strong>price feeds</strong> and Chainlink <strong>direct requests</strong> (Any API).</p></li><li><p>Show you how to find a Chainlink oracle to support your price feed.</p></li><li><p>Explore use cases for Chainlink price feeds.</p></li></ol><center><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e75kwGzvtnI" frameborder="0"></iframe></center><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="chainlinks-decentralized-data-model"><strong>Chainlink's Decentralized Data Model</strong><a href="#chainlinks-decentralized-data-model" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to chainlinks-decentralized-data-model" title="Direct link to chainlinks-decentralized-data-model">​</a></h2><p>In our previous article, we explored how Web3 developers can collaborate with Chainlink node operators to <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Requesting-A-Custom-Chainlink-Data-Feed-Using-Any-API" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">create a custom data feed via Chainlink's basic request model</a> - also known as "direct requests" or "Any API". One of the primary benefits of this approach is that data is only written when requested by the consumer, saving on fees. This model uses a pull-based system to retrieve data on-chain from any internet source (Any API) at any desired frequency and is typically served by just a single Chainlink oracle.</p><p>This article will shift gears and instead delve into Chainlink's decentralized data model. We will explore how this model facilitates the establishment of custom decentralized oracle networks (DON) that compile data on-chain from multiple data sources through a decentralized network of independent node operators.</p><p>Ultimately, Chainlink price feeds allow data to be updated automatically within your smart contract based on a certain set of conditions, ensuring that your data is always fresh whenever your Web3 application needs it.</p><p>Chainlink's Decentralized Data Model aggregates data from multiple sources to ensure accuracy and reliability for smart contracts.</p><p>Offchain Reporting (OCR) and Flux Aggregator (FluxAgg) are two such protocols, with OCR optimizing for efficiency by processing data and reaching consensus off-chain, reducing costs and improving update speed. Flux Aggregator, its predecessor, performs a similar aggregation, but directly on the blockchain. <strong>This article will focus on the Flux Aggregator protocol.</strong></p><p>The decentralized data model introduces a number of features:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Security:</strong> The DON aggregates data from multiple Chainlink oracles, reducing the risk of manipulation by any single oracle, and helping to eliminate single points of failure.</p></li><li><p><strong>Reliability:</strong> The DON maintains high availability and reliability of data feeds, even if some data providers are compromised or incorrect.</p></li><li><p><strong>Accuracy:</strong> Sophisticated algorithms filter out data anomalies, ensuring the data reflects true market conditions or measurable parameters accurately.</p></li><li><p><strong>Trust-Minimization:</strong> All operations and data sources are transparent and verifiable, building trust among both users and developers.</p></li><li><p><strong>Customization:</strong> Offers flexibility in specifying data sources, update frequencies, and aggregation methods to meet specific project requirements.</p></li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="components-of-the-decentralized-data-model"><strong>Components of the Decentralized Data Model</strong><a href="#components-of-the-decentralized-data-model" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to components-of-the-decentralized-data-model" title="Direct link to components-of-the-decentralized-data-model">​</a></h3><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/flux-agg-article/Flux_Aggregator_Architecture_Diagram.webp" alt="Chainlink Flux Aggregator Architecture Diagram" class="img_ev3q"></p><blockquote><p>In the architecture depicted above, three independent Chainlink oracle teams are showcased solely for illustrative purposes. In practice, any number and combination of independent Chainlink oracles can be employed. The flexibility in this arrangement is mainly motivated by considerations such as trust-minimization, reliability, and security budgets.
Additionally, each Chainlink oracle can (and should) utilize a different external data source or API endpoint if at all possible. This provides decentralization at the external data source layer. For more on this topic, we recommend referring to Chainlink's article on <a href="https://blog.chain.link/levels-of-data-aggregation-in-chainlink-price-feeds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the 3 levels of aggregation for price feeds</a>.</p></blockquote><p>The components of the decentralized data model include:</p><p><strong>Consumer Contract:</strong> A Consumer contract refers to any contract that utilizes Chainlink price feeds to access the data aggregated on-chain. To access this data, consumer contracts need to instantiate the appropriate <a href="https://github.com/smartcontractkit/chainlink/blob/master/contracts/src/v0.8/shared/interfaces/AggregatorV3Interface.sol" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AggregatorV3Interface contract</a> and execute one of its available functions.</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    ...</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    AggregatorV3Interface feed = AggregatorV3Interface(address);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    return feed.latestRoundData();</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><blockquote><p>Off-chain (Web 2.0) applications are also capable of utilizing price feeds. For further information, refer to the example code in JavaScript and Python on the <a href="https://docs.chain.link/data-feeds/price-feeds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Using Data Feeds</a> page.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Proxy Contract:</strong> Proxy contracts serve as on-chain intermediaries that point to a specific aggregator associated with a data feed. This approach allows for the aggregator to be updated seamlessly, ensuring that contracts consuming the service experience no disruptions.</p><p>While the design of proxy contracts may differ across various data feeds, a frequently used example is the <a href="https://github.com/smartcontractkit/chainlink/blob/master/contracts/src/v0.7/dev/AggregatorProxy.sol" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AggregatorProxy.sol contract</a> available on Github.</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    ...</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    contract AggregatorProxy is AggregatorProxyInterface, ConfirmedOwner {</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p><strong>FluxAggregator Contract:</strong> This refers to the contract that periodically obtains data updates from the oracle network. It stores this aggregated data onchain, enabling consumers to retrieve the data and act upon it within the same transaction. This data can be accessed through the Data Feed address and by interfacing with the <a href="https://github.com/smartcontractkit/chainlink/blob/master/contracts/src/v0.6/interfaces/AggregatorV3Interface.sol" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AggregatorV3Interface contract</a>.</p><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">      function latestRoundData()</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        external</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        view</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        returns (</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">          uint80 roundId,</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">          int256 answer,</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">          uint256 startedAt,</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">          uint256 updatedAt,</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">          uint80 answeredInRound</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        );</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>Typically, the client (the Web3 project or team in need of the price feed) is responsible for maintaining and deploying the FluxAggregator contract. However, Chainlink oracles (node operators) can assist with the deployment process. It is also up to the client to keep the contract funded with LINK tokens to guarantee payment for the Chainlink oracles' services.</p><p>For additional information on the AggregatorV3Interface API, please reference <a href="https://docs.chain.link/data-feeds/api-reference#aggregatorv3interface" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink's documentation</a>.</p><p><strong>Chainlink Oracle:</strong> The Chainlink node (or oracle) is an off-chain, Go-based runtime provided by Chainlink Labs. Oracles are typically operated by professional Chainlink node operator teams who specialize in deploying and maintaining Chainlink oracle infrastructure. They work in tandem with external adapters to collect data from various external sources, aggregate it to ensure accuracy and reliability, and then feed the requested data back to the on-chain aggregator contract.</p><p>Chainlink oracles run the Flux Monitor job specification, as demonstrated in the following example:</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/flux-agg-article/Flux_Monitor_Job_Spec.webp" alt="Chainlink oracle Flux Monitor job spec" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>This job specification outlines the criteria for data feed updates, including the sources of observation utilized and the frequency of updates on the blockchain. For more information on the Flux Monitor job spec, feel free to <a href="https://docs.chain.link/chainlink-nodes/oracle-jobs/all-jobs#flux-monitor-jobs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">review the fields here</a>. These fields can be tuned as necessary as per the Web3 project's requirements</p><blockquote><p>Oracles that participate in the data aggregation process are compensated for their work, typically in the form of the Chainlink (LINK) token. This incentivizes oracles to provide accurate and timely data, ensuring the reliability of the data feed.</p></blockquote><p><strong>External Adapters:</strong> External adapters facilitate custom logic for requests as HTTP services that can be written in any programming language, handling tasks from authenticated data access to IoT processing and bank payments. They bridge various data sources, including enterprise systems and other blockchains, ensuring broad connectivity beyond simple HTTP requests.</p><p>Chainlink's list of external adapters can be found <a href="https://github.com/smartcontractkit/external-adapters-js/tree/main/packages/sources" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p><p><strong>Data Sources:</strong> Data sources refer to the external providers from which Chainlink oracles retrieve information. These can include financial market data, weather reports, sports outcomes, or any other real-world data that smart contracts may require.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="flux-aggregator-round-system"><strong>Flux Aggregator Round System</strong><a href="#flux-aggregator-round-system" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to flux-aggregator-round-system" title="Direct link to flux-aggregator-round-system">​</a></h3><p>The Aggregator round system is a mechanism used by Chainlink to update data feeds in a decentralized and secure manner. Here's an overview of how it functions:</p><ol><li><strong>Round Initiation:</strong> A round represents a cycle in which data is aggregated and updated. Rounds can be initiated based on two main conditions: the Deviation Threshold and the Heartbeat Threshold.</li></ol><ul><li><p><strong>Deviation Threshold:</strong> This condition checks if the difference between the latest on-chain data and the new off-chain data collected by the oracles exceeds a pre-defined threshold. If the data deviates more than this threshold, it triggers a new round to update the on-chain data to reflect the more accurate, recent off-chain data.</p></li><li><p><strong>Heartbeat Threshold:</strong> This condition triggers a new round after a specified time has passed since the last update, regardless of data deviation. This ensures that the data feed is updated regularly, maintaining its relevance and accuracy over time.</p></li></ul><ol start="2"><li><p><strong>Data Collection:</strong> Once a new round is initiated, participating oracles collect data from their off-chain sources. These sources can vary based on the data feed, ranging from financial market prices to real-world asset data.</p></li><li><p><strong>Data Aggregation:</strong> After collecting the data, each oracle reports its findings back to the FluxAggregator contract. The contract then aggregates this data using a predefined method, such as taking the median or average, to determine the most accurate representation of the data collected from all participating oracles.</p></li><li><p><strong>Data Update:</strong> The aggregated result is then updated on-chain, becoming the latest data point for the feed. This data then becomes available for smart contracts and other on-chain entities to use, ensuring they have access to accurate and timely information.</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="steps-for-developing-a-custom-price-feed-with-fluxaggregator">Steps For Developing a Custom Price Feed With FluxAggregator<a href="#steps-for-developing-a-custom-price-feed-with-fluxaggregator" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Steps For Developing a Custom Price Feed With FluxAggregator" title="Direct link to Steps For Developing a Custom Price Feed With FluxAggregator">​</a></h2><p>While we won't dive into the exact deployment process for the FluxAggregator protocol in this article (stay tuned for a future release on this), we will provide the high-level steps.</p><p>The steps for integrating a custom Chainlink price feed are:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Locate a Chainlink node operator</strong>: Join the <strong>#operator-requests</strong> channel of the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/chainlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Official Discord server</a>, or reach out to us (LinkWell Nodes) <a href="https://linkwellnodes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p></li><li><p><strong>Explain your requirements</strong>: Tell your chosen Chainlink oracle about your Web3 project's requirements for a price feed. These requirements can typically include the price feed pair, the number of node operators desired in the DON, and the data sources to be utilized. Once the requirements are clear, the node operator can assist you (if needed) in initially setting up the FluxAggregator contract on your selected testnet, configuring it, and supplying the price feed address to utilize the price feed in the consumer contract.</p></li><li><p><strong>Expand your oracle network</strong>: Following comprehensive testing, you'll want to enlist additional Chainlink oracles in your price feed DON. Often, your chosen Chainlink oracle will have their own network of contacts they can reach out to for additional support.</p></li><li><p><strong>Deploy your price feed</strong>: Deploy the FluxAggregator contract on mainnet alongside your Web3 application.</p></li></ol><p>The bulk of the integration effort takes place on the Chainlink oracle's end, but from a consumer perspective, it's as simple as that!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="price-feeds-vs-direct-requests-any-api">Price Feeds vs. Direct Requests (Any API)<a href="#price-feeds-vs-direct-requests-any-api" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Price Feeds vs. Direct Requests (Any API)" title="Direct link to Price Feeds vs. Direct Requests (Any API)">​</a></h2><p>While this article focuses primarily on price feeds, it may be helpful to offer a comparison with a different type of Chainlink request: <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/Direct-Request-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">direct requests</a> (also known as 'Any API').</p><p><strong>Price Feeds (i.e., Flux Aggregator)</strong>:</p><p><strong>Pros</strong>:</p><ul><li><p>Data is always up-to-date, as it is re-written on-chain whenever a certain % change in value occurs (i.e., whenever a 5% price deviation occurs).</p></li><li><p>Can utilize multiple Chainlink oracles to serve your price feed, for enhanced decentralization and trust-minimization.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Cons</strong>:</p><ul><li><p>More expensive, as you pay for every on-chain update of your data.</p></li><li><p>Longer and more complicated set-up, which potentially involves finding and communicating your requirements to multiple oracle teams.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Direct Requests (Any API):</strong></p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/flux-agg-article/Chainlink_Direct_Request_Architecture.webp" alt="Basic Request Model (Any API) Architecture" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Pros</strong>:</p><ul><li><p>Cheaper, since you only pay for what you use (data is updated only when you request it, or on a set schedule).</p></li><li><p>Quick and easy setup (you can be up and running within minutes using our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">self-service documentation</a>).</p></li><li><p>Can return any data type on-chain, whereas price feeds are limited to the <em>int</em> data type.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Cons</strong>:</p><ul><li><p>Takes at least 1 block for the data to appear on-chain, depending on the blockchain.</p></li><li><p>Typically not as decentralized or trust-minimized as a price feed, although developers have the option to <a href="https://medium.com/linkwell-nodes/chainlinks-basic-direct-request-model-chainlink-oracle-architectures-explained-996e6e9d2bb4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">utilize multiple Chainlink oracles in a DON</a>, if desired.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="where-can-i-find-a-chainlink-oracle"><strong>Where Can I Find a Chainlink Oracle?</strong><a href="#where-can-i-find-a-chainlink-oracle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to where-can-i-find-a-chainlink-oracle" title="Direct link to where-can-i-find-a-chainlink-oracle">​</a></h2><p>As of the time of writing, there lacks a centralized marketplace for Chainlink oracles (market.link has been deprecated). As such, the primary avenue for finding a Chainlink oracle / node operator is by sending a chat within the <strong>#operator-requests</strong> channel of the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/chainlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Official Discord server</a>. Additionally, a simple Google search can yield information about the various Chainlink node operators and the services they publicly offer.</p><blockquote><p>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink community oracle, providing custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions across virtually all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.
Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a>, or hop into the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkWell Nodes Discord server</a> and ask for help!</p></blockquote><p><strong>What to Look For In a Chainlink Oracle (Node Operator)?</strong></p><p>Working with a knowledgeable and competent Chainlink node operator can greatly streamline the process, allowing you or your team to allocate resources more efficiently to your Web3 application. Furthermore, your Chainlink node operator should possess the expertise to assist in crafting your smart contract code, conducting code reviews, and suggesting gas optimization strategies within your smart contract. This will not only save you time, but can also preserve valuable funds in sending test requests to your Chainlink oracle.</p><p>Here's what you should look for when it comes to a Chainlink node operator:</p><ol><li><p>Proven track record.</p></li><li><p>Trustworthy and reliable.</p></li><li><p>Strong communication skills.</p></li><li><p>Transparent and clearly-defined pricing.</p></li><li><p>Continuous monitoring of each data feed.</p></li><li><p>Reliable, secure, and redundant infrastructure.</p></li><li><p>Knowledgeable in Solidity and smart contract design.</p></li><li><p>A well-defined process for requesting custom price feeds.</p></li><li><p>A clear service-level agreement (SLA) for their price feed performance.</p></li></ol><p>Ultimately, the responsibility is yours to diligently vet and select a Chainlink oracle (or oracles) who align with the characteristics above.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="price-feed-example-use-cases">Price Feed Example Use Cases<a href="#price-feed-example-use-cases" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Price Feed Example Use Cases" title="Direct link to Price Feed Example Use Cases">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="money-markets"><strong>Money Markets</strong><a href="#money-markets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to money-markets" title="Direct link to money-markets">​</a></h3><p>Blockchain money markets are a key part of the decentralized finance (DeFi) ecosystem, using smart contracts to connect lenders looking to earn on their digital assets with borrowers seeking capital. These platforms increase the utility and liquidity of cryptocurrencies by enabling active lending and borrowing, thereby enhancing the liquidity and utility of digital assets across the board.</p><p>The operational efficiency and financial stability of these platforms hinge on the accurate and real-time valuation of assets, necessitating the integration of reliable price feeds. This is where sophisticated solutions like Chainlink price feeds come into play. They provide up-to-the-minute market data for a wide array of cryptocurrencies, thereby enabling protocols such as Aave and Compound to precisely assess the value of collateral and debt within their systems. This critical functionality allows these protocols to execute timely liquidations for undercollateralized positions, ensuring the financial integrity and solvency of the platform.</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/flux-agg-article/Chainlink_Aave_Price_Feed.webp" alt="Chainlink Aave Price Feed Example Use Case" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In essence, blockchain-based money markets not only facilitate a dynamic environment for the DeFi community to lend and borrow assets efficiently but also underscore the importance of accurate price feeds in maintaining the economic stability and trustworthiness of these platforms. Through the strategic use of Chainlink price feeds, these protocols are able to uphold their commitment to safeguarding user assets while promoting healthy liquidity and fair market practices.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="asset-tokenization"><strong>Asset Tokenization</strong><a href="#asset-tokenization" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to asset-tokenization" title="Direct link to asset-tokenization">​</a></h3><p>Tokenizing real-world assets, from currencies to stocks, bonds, real estate, and gold, opens up possibilities for increased investor access, improved transparency, and enhanced market liquidity.</p><p>For the successful tokenization of assets, the availability of accurate, onchain market price data via Chainlink price feeds is crucial. Take, for instance, the PAXG Chainlink price feed for tokenized gold, which allows for the creation of secure markets around physical gold. Moreover, Paxos leverages Chainlink Proof of Reserve to assure onchain that its tokenized gold offerings are fully backed by offchain gold reserves, fostering high-integrity markets for these assets.</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/flux-agg-article/Decentralized_Oracle_Network_Price_Feed.webp" alt="Chainlink Price Feeds Oracle Network" class="img_ev3q"></p><blockquote><p>For additional use cases of Chainlink price feeds, we highly recommend checking out Chainlink's article on the <a href="https://blog.chain.link/smart-contract-use-cases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">77+ smart contract use cases enabled by Chainlink</a>.</p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong><a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to conclusion" title="Direct link to conclusion">​</a></h2><p>Chainlink price feeds provide a way of ensuring your on-chain data is always fresh, by automatically updating your smart contract whenever a certain threshold criteria is met. They also provide a mechanism for further decentralizing your data feed, by allowing your data to be aggregated from multiple Chainlink oracles at a time.</p><p>In comparison to the <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/Direct-Request-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Direct Request</a> (Any API) model, Chainlink price feeds are more expensive, as they are typically updated more frequently on-chain, and involve greater work and coordination to set up, although this may be worth it for some security-intensive and enterprise-grade applications.</p><p>The rigorous emphasis on blockchain data integrity and security has elevated Chainlink price feeds to the forefront as the most widely-adopted oracle solution within the DeFi sector. Moreover, Chainlink price feeds are tailored to expand in tandem with DeFi's evolution, supporting its ascent to become the underlying technology for major global financial markets, encompassing billions to trillions of dollars in value.</p><blockquote><p>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink community oracle, providing custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions across virtually all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.
Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a>, or hop into the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkWell Nodes Discord server</a> and ask for help!
Disclaimer: all views and opinions expressed in this article are strictly our own.</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" src="/assets/images/lw-banner_1080x606-c6d84e1ae6e43af8c26ee04d238969be.webp" title="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" width="1080" height="606" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="chainlink oracle" term="chainlink oracle"/>
        <category label="smart contracts" term="smart contracts"/>
        <category label="price feed" term="price feed"/>
        <category label="web3" term="web3"/>
        <category label="blockchain" term="blockchain"/>
        <category label="decentralized" term="decentralized"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chainlink Any API: Building a Custom Oracle Network]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Chainlink-Basic-Request-Model-Architectures</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Chainlink-Basic-Request-Model-Architectures"/>
        <updated>2024-02-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Chainlink's Basic Request Model: How Web3 developers can design Chainlink oracle networks for reliable real-world data in their apps.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="chainlinks-basic-direct-request-model-chainlink-oracle-architectures-explained">Chainlink's Basic (Direct) Request Model: Chainlink Oracle Architectures Explained<a href="#chainlinks-basic-direct-request-model-chainlink-oracle-architectures-explained" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Chainlink's Basic (Direct) Request Model: Chainlink Oracle Architectures Explained" title="Direct link to Chainlink's Basic (Direct) Request Model: Chainlink Oracle Architectures Explained">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Chainlink Basic Request Model Architecture Header" src="/assets/images/Header-8a8f12d8b195786445e06847c058bc25.webp" title="Chainlink Basic Request Model Architectures" width="800" height="600" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="introduction"><strong>Introduction</strong><a href="#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to introduction" title="Direct link to introduction">​</a></h2><p>Chainlink's basic request model - previously known as the "direct request model" - is a bit of a misnomer.</p><p>While this model can indeed be viewed as the "basic" building block of Chainlink oracle requests - especially in comparison to some of its more recent counterparts such as Functions, Off-Chain Reporting (OCR), and the Cross-Chain Interoperability Protocol (CCIP) - the Basic Request Model supports a number of different deployment architectures that allow it to connect your smart contract to virtually anywhere on the internet.</p><p>In this article, we'll unravel the intricacies of Chainlink's basic request model, shedding light on the various architectures / design patterns that Web3 developers can implement to incorporate reliable, real-world data into their decentralized applications.</p><blockquote><p><strong><em>Who are we?</em></strong>
LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink oracle specializing in secure, decentralized, data feeds and self-service oracle solutions across virtually all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.
Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a>, or hop into the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkWell Nodes Discord server</a> and ask for help!</p></blockquote><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="chainlinks-basic-request-model-aka-direct-request-model"><strong>Chainlink's Basic Request Model (A.K.A. Direct Request Model)</strong><a href="#chainlinks-basic-request-model-aka-direct-request-model" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to chainlinks-basic-request-model-aka-direct-request-model" title="Direct link to chainlinks-basic-request-model-aka-direct-request-model">​</a></h3><p>This article will provide an in-depth analysis of the components that make up the basic request model. Subsequently, we will delve into the architectures that developers have at their disposal for their Web3 applications.</p><blockquote><p>For a high-level overview of the basic request model (direct request model), you can also visit our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/Direct-Request-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website's documentation</a>, our previous article on <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Requesting-A-Custom-Chainlink-Data-Feed-Using-Any-API" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">building custom Chainlink data feeds using Any API</a>, or our exploration of <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Chainlink-Any-API-Direct-Requests-Vs-Functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Functions Versus Direct Request Jobs</a>.</p></blockquote><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/CL_DR_Model_Single_Chainlink_Oracle.webp" alt="Basic Request (Direct Request) Model Workflow Single Chainlink Oracle" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The components of the basic request model implementation include the following:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Consumer Contract / <a href="https://github.com/smartcontractkit/chainlink/blob/master/contracts/src/v0.8/ChainlinkClient.sol" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ChainlinkClient.sol</a>:</strong> The consumer contract (or "client") is a contract that enables smart contracts to consume data from Chainlink oracles. It's available in the Chainlink smart contract library, which can be <a href="https://docs.chain.link/resources/create-a-chainlinked-project" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">installed using one of several package managers</a>. The client initiates a request to a known Chainlink oracle by utilizing the <strong>transferAndCall()</strong> function. Your request data is encoded and passed to this function call. The initiation of this call, specifically within the <strong>ChainlinkClient</strong> contract, is executed through the <strong>sendChainlinkRequest() </strong>or<strong> sendChainlinkRequestTo()</strong> function.</p></li><li><p><strong>Chainlink (LINK) Token:</strong> LINK is a token that adheres to the ERC-677 standard, incorporating the <strong>transferAndCall()</strong> function. This function enables the simultaneous transfer of tokens and the initiation of specific logic within the receiving contract, all within a single transaction. The sent LINK token is used to pay the corresponding node operator for fulfilling your request. More information on the LINK token and LINK token contracts can be found <a href="https://docs.chain.link/resources/link-token-contracts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p></li><li><p><strong>Oracle/Operator Contract:</strong> The oracle (or operator) contract is a contract deployed by any team operating a Chainlink node (oracle), and operates in tandem with the corresponding Chainlink node(s). Oracle contracts manage on-chain <strong>requests</strong> initiated through the LINK token by using the <strong>onTokenTransfer()</strong> function as a <strong>LinkTokenReceiver</strong>. When this function is executed, the oracle contract emits an <strong>OracleRequest</strong> event, conveying essential information about the request to the Chainlink oracle. This event serves as a for the off-chain oracle node to take the necessary actions in fulfilling the client's request. To <strong>fulfill</strong> requests, the oracle contract contains the <strong>fulfillOracleRequest()</strong> function, which is called by the oracle node once the requested result (data) is ready to be written to the blockchain. This function sends the result back to the <strong>ChainlinkClient</strong> contract, by executing the callback (fulfillment) function provided by the client within the initial request.</p></li><li><p><strong>Chainlink Node (oracle):</strong> The Chainlink node (or oracle) is an off-chain, Go-based runtime provided by Chainlink Labs that actively monitors events emitted by its associated on-chain <strong>oracle contract</strong>. Upon detecting an <strong>OracleRequest</strong> event, the node utilizes the emitted data to execute a specific request workflow (or "job"). One of the most common job types for a node involves making a GET request to an API, parsing the response, converting the result into blockchain-compatible format, and finally submitting it back to the oracle contract through an on-chain transaction, utilizing the <strong>fulfillOracleRequest()</strong> function.</p></li><li><p><strong>External Adapters:</strong> External adapters exist to execute any custom logic required for the request. External adapters are essentially HTTP services (programmed in any language), and thus they can execute whatever custom logic necessary for the request. Common workflows handled by external adapters include passing authenticated requests to premium data providers, processing IoT sensor information, handling bank payments, communicating with enterprise back-ends, other blockchain networks, and connecting to various other data sources that might not be accessible via a simple HTTP request.</p></li><li><p><strong>API (i.e., the internet):</strong> An API endpoint is the specific URL or data service (i.e., CoinMarketCap) to which the offchain oracle (or external adapter) makes its request for data. In the context of Chainlink, an API is the source of the data that you'd like written to your smart contract.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="basic-request-model-oracle-architectures"><strong>Basic Request Model Oracle Architectures</strong><a href="#basic-request-model-oracle-architectures" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to basic-request-model-oracle-architectures" title="Direct link to basic-request-model-oracle-architectures">​</a></h2><p>The following architectures depict the sequential progression of a Web3 developer manually triggering the request function within their consumer contract. It commences with the most straightforward oracle architecture - a direct request to a single Chainlink oracle owned and operated by a single Chainlink node operator, and advances to the most advanced architecture - a direct request to multiple Chainlink oracles owned and operated by multiple independent Chainlink node operators.</p><blockquote><p>To simplify the forthcoming architectural diagrams, we have opted to exclude the potential integration of other Chainlink services, including VRF, Automation, CCIP, official Chainlink data feeds, and others. Nevertheless, we advise incorporating Chainlink Automation, at the very least, to streamline the request pipeline based on specific external triggers.
<strong>Moreover, depending on the requirements of your Web3 project, we strongly suggest integrating any and all Chainlink services necessary for the project's success!</strong></p></blockquote><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="architecture-1-direct-request-to-a-single-chainlink-oracle"><strong>Architecture 1: Direct Request to a Single Chainlink Oracle</strong><a href="#architecture-1-direct-request-to-a-single-chainlink-oracle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to architecture-1-direct-request-to-a-single-chainlink-oracle" title="Direct link to architecture-1-direct-request-to-a-single-chainlink-oracle">​</a></h3><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/CL_DR_Model_Single_Chainlink_Oracle.webp" alt="Basic Request (Direct Request) Model Single Chainlink Oracle" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Architecture 1</strong> is the simplest version of the basic request model. The sequence begins with a Web3 developer triggering a request (through the on-chain consumer contract) to a single Chainlink oracle owned by a single Chainlink node operator. The Chainlink oracle fetches the requested data and submits the obtained result back on-chain.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Important note</strong>: Reputable node operators will run multiple Chainlink nodes in a redundant cluster, having one "primary" oracle responding to requests, and at least one "backup" oracle operating in passive mode, ready to take over in case of a failure in the primary oracle.
At LinkWell Nodes, we operate all of our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/mainnets" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mainnet oracles</a> in redundant, fault-tolerant, location-independent clusters, ensuring that your workload will complete on time, every time.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Simplified configuration and deployment (can be up &amp; running within the day).</p></li><li><p>Most cost-effective choice.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul><li>Centralization at the oracle team layer (requires you to find an oracle team that you trust).</li></ul><p><strong>When to Implement?</strong></p><ul><li><p>Your Web3 project operates on a constrained budget, limiting support for requests to multiple Chainlink oracles.</p></li><li><p>You would benefit from an oracle team designing and implementing the request for you.</p></li><li><p>Chainlink Functions doesn't support your use case or network.</p></li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="architecture-2-direct-request-to-multiple-chainlink-oracles"><strong>Architecture 2: Direct Request to Multiple Chainlink Oracles</strong><a href="#architecture-2-direct-request-to-multiple-chainlink-oracles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to architecture-2-direct-request-to-multiple-chainlink-oracles" title="Direct link to architecture-2-direct-request-to-multiple-chainlink-oracles">​</a></h3><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/CL_DR_Model_Multi_LW_Chainlink_Oracle.webp" alt="Basic Request (Direct Request) Model Workflow Multiple LinkWell Chainlink Oracles" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Architecture 2</strong> closely resembles <strong>Architecture 1</strong>, with the primary difference lying in the inclusion of multiple Chainlink oracles (linked to separate oracle/operator contracts) handling the request. These oracles are owned and overseen by the same Chainlink node operator.</p><blockquote><p>With this architecture, each Chainlink oracle can (and should) utilize a different external data source or API endpoint if possible. This provides decentralization and enhanced reliability at the external data source layer. For more on this topic, we recommend referring to Chainlink's article on <a href="https://blog.chain.link/levels-of-data-aggregation-in-chainlink-price-feeds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the 3 levels of aggregation for price feeds</a>.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Enhanced decentralization at the Chainlink oracle layer.</p></li><li><p>Increased reliability of the request pipeline.</p></li><li><p>Decentralization at the external data source layer.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Increased intricacy in configuration and deployment.</p></li><li><p>Centralization at the oracle team layer (requires trust in the oracle team that you have chosen).</p></li><li><p>The per-request cost scales by N(x), where "N" is the number of independent Chainlink oracles fulfilling the request.</p></li></ul><p><strong>When to Implement?</strong></p><ul><li><p>For mainnet use cases, this architecture presents itself as a strong candidate, particularly when explicit trust is vested in the selected Chainlink node operator.</p></li><li><p>You would benefit from oracle teams designing and implementing the request for you.</p></li><li><p>Chainlink Functions doesn't support your use case or network.</p></li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="architecture-3-direct-request-to-a-multiple-chainlink-oracles-across-independent-chainlink-node-operators"><strong>Architecture 3: Direct Request to a Multiple Chainlink Oracles Across Independent Chainlink Node Operators</strong><a href="#architecture-3-direct-request-to-a-multiple-chainlink-oracles-across-independent-chainlink-node-operators" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to architecture-3-direct-request-to-a-multiple-chainlink-oracles-across-independent-chainlink-node-operators" title="Direct link to architecture-3-direct-request-to-a-multiple-chainlink-oracles-across-independent-chainlink-node-operators">​</a></h3><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/CL_DR_Model_Four_Chainlink_Oracle.webp" alt="Basic Request (Direct Request) Model Workflow Multiple Independent Chainlink Oracles" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Architecture 3</strong> is distinct from <strong>Architecture 2</strong> in that it incorporates multiple independent Chainlink oracle teams. Diverging from previous designs, this architecture embraces the essence of decentralization, emulating a decentralized oracle network (DON) as seen with Chainlink's official protocols.</p><blockquote><p>In the architecture depicted above, four independent Chainlink oracle teams are showcased solely for illustrative purposes. In practice, any number and combination of independent Chainlink oracles can be employed. The flexibility in this arrangement is mainly motivated by considerations such as trust-minimization, decentralization, and cost factors.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Maximal trust-minimization across all layers.</p></li><li><p>Decentralization across all layers.</p></li><li><p>Maximal reliability of the request pipeline.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Requires you to find and reach out to multiple oracle teams, and convince them to implement a decentralized oracle network for your request. The fees and time commitment of such designs can be high.</p></li><li><p>Increased intricacy in configuration and deployment.</p></li><li><p>The per-request cost scales by N(x), where "N" is the number of independent Chainlink oracles fulfilling the request.</p></li></ul><p><strong>When to Implement?</strong></p><ul><li><p>When maximum decentralization, reliability, and trust-minimization are a priority for your Web3 application.</p></li><li><p>Chainlink Functions doesn't support your use case or network.</p></li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="bonus-architecture-direct-request-without-a-link-fee"><strong>Bonus Architecture: Direct Request Without a LINK Fee</strong><a href="#bonus-architecture-direct-request-without-a-link-fee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to bonus-architecture-direct-request-without-a-link-fee" title="Direct link to bonus-architecture-direct-request-without-a-link-fee">​</a></h3><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/Chainlink_DR_Model_Single_Chainlink_Oracle_No_LINK_Fee.webp" alt="Basic Request (Direct Request) Model Single Chainlink Oracle No LINK Fee" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As a notable feature of the basic request model, we are introducing a bonus architecture where Chainlink node operators have the option to eliminate the LINK fee for each request and opt for alternative forms of payment, such as fiat or other L1/L2 tokens. <strong>This methodology can be implemented within any of the above architectures in this article.</strong></p><p>Additionally, this opens the door to innovative payment models as demonstrated by the following:</p><ul><li><p>Bulk up-front payments for a set number of requests to the Chainlink oracle.</p></li><li><p>Discounts for high volume use cases.</p></li><li><p>Monthly flat fees for unlimited/exclusive use of the Chainlink oracle, where on-chain oracle data submission costs are reimbursed to the node operator by the consumer.</p></li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="final-considerations"><strong>Final Considerations</strong><a href="#final-considerations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to final-considerations" title="Direct link to final-considerations">​</a></h3><p>We'd like to leave four final takeaways for your consideration when deciding to implement Chainlink's basic request model:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Trust-Minimization and Decentralization:</strong> When choosing your architecture, it's necessary to put some thought into what aspects of your design require decentralization - datacenter decentralization, oracle team decentralization, and data source decentralization, are all key components that one must consider.</p></li><li><p><strong>On-Chain Reporting Speeds:</strong> A fundamental advantage of the basic request model for Web3 use cases - particularly those reliant on swift on-chain reporting speeds - lies in the ability of direct request jobs to provide oracle request results on-chain within 1–3 blocks of the initial request.</p></li><li><p><strong>Data Aggregation with the Basic Request Model:</strong> In all architectures, Web3 developers possess the flexibility to aggregate the data received by their request, whether through the usage of an external adapter, or an aggregator contract.</p></li><li><p><strong>Functions:</strong> While Chainlink's basic request model has successfully served hundreds if not thousands of Web3 projects since Chainlink's launch, <a href="https://docs.chain.link/chainlink-functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Functions</a> represents a viable alternative. While Functions is still in mainnet BETA and may not be recommended for production workloads, Web3 developers may want to review Functions before opting for the basic request model.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong><a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to conclusion" title="Direct link to conclusion">​</a></h2><p>Chainlink's basic request model (also called "direct requests") represents a capable and flexible method of retrieving off-chain (i.e., internet) data and writing it to your contract.</p><p>Within the basic request model, several different architectures and design patterns exist, all of which juggle trade-offs in terms of centralization, cost, and complexity. While other Chainlink services may offer a different presentation of the above trade-offs, the basic request model continues to be one of the fundamental building blocks that make Chainlink so versatile at solving the blockchain oracle problem.</p><p>We trust that this article sheds helps to shed some light on the various Chainlink oracle architectures available within the basic request model, and offers valuable insights to Web3 developers looking to integrate real-world data into their blockchain smart contracts.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Why Chainlink?</strong>
Smart contracts are limited from directly interacting with the internet, creating what's known as the blockchain <a href="https://chain.link/education-hub/oracle-problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">oracle problem</a>. This hurdle represents one of the greatest limitations in building Web3 smart contracts.
Hybrid smart contracts solve this by using oracles as middleware - enabling external data publishing &amp; retrieval, and scalable off-chain computations. Oracles act as a two-way bridge, enhancing connectivity while providing security against single points of failure.
Chainlink - the industry standard Web3 oracle platform - is the most widely used decentralized oracle network, securing over $75B in value across a diverse assortment of blockchains. It operates as an ecosystem of independent decentralized oracle networks (DONs), guaranteeing robust and versatile oracle services.</p></blockquote><hr><blockquote><p>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink community oracle, providing custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions across virtually all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.
Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a>, or hop into the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkWell Nodes Discord server</a> and ask for help!</p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" src="/assets/images/lw-banner_1080x606-c6d84e1ae6e43af8c26ee04d238969be.webp" title="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" width="1080" height="606" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="chainlink" term="chainlink"/>
        <category label="smart contracts" term="smart contracts"/>
        <category label="decentralized oracles" term="decentralized oracles"/>
        <category label="web3" term="web3"/>
        <category label="blockchain" term="blockchain"/>
        <category label="node operator" term="node operator"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Request a Custom Any API Chainlink Data Feed: A 7 Step Guide For Web3 Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Requesting-A-Custom-Chainlink-Data-Feed-Using-Any-API</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Requesting-A-Custom-Chainlink-Data-Feed-Using-Any-API"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we explore the 7 steps that Web3 developers can follow for integrating real world data from Chainlink oracles into their smart contracts.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Chainlink Any API Data Feed" src="/assets/images/Header-bc9891a313def6faadc04fe1c09ce64e.webp" title="Chainlink Any API Data Feed" width="720" height="235" class="img_ev3q"></p><center><small><em>Credit: <a href="https://blog.chain.link/apis-smart-contracts-and-how-to-connect-them/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://blog.chain.link/apis-smart-contracts-and-how-to-connect-them/</a></em></small></center><p></p><p>Smart contracts that integrate Chainlink data feeds are far more capable than those that don't.</p><p>Since its launch in 2017, Chainlink - the industry standard Web3 services platform - has curated an extensive array of <a href="https://docs.chain.link/data-feeds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official data feeds</a>, among a myriad of other powerful services, providing developers with a seamless integration of real-world information into their applications. However, the dynamic nature of Web3 applications often demands access to data beyond what official Chainlink feeds offer. This is where custom Chainlink <a href="https://docs.chain.link/any-api/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Any API</a> data feeds step in, catering to the unique requirements of diverse smart contract applications. The process for requesting a custom Any API Chainlink data feed, however, hasn't always been clearly defined.</p><p>That's why we've gone through great lengths to make the process as seamless as possible for Web3 developers looking to integrate Chainlink's Any API capabilities.</p><blockquote><p><strong> <em>Why Chainlink?</em> </strong></p><p><em>Blockchain consensus mechanisms limit smart contracts from directly interacting with the internet, creating the blockchain <a href="https://chain.link/education-hub/oracle-problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">oracle problem</a>. This hurdle represents one of the greatest limitations to representing everyday contracts on the blockchain.</em></p><p><em>Hybrid smart contracts solve this by using oracles as middleware - enabling external data publishing &amp; retrieval, and scalable off-chain computations. Oracles act as a two-way bridge, enhancing connectivity while providing security against single points of failure.</em></p><p><em>Chainlink - the industry standard Web3 services platform - is the most widely used decentralized oracle network, securing significant value across a diverse assortment of blockchains and use cases. It operates as an ecosystem with independent decentralized oracle networks, guaranteeing robust and versatile oracle services.</em></p></blockquote><p><strong>Prerequisites For Making An Any API Request</strong></p><p>There are three Web3 technologies that you'll need to have in place before making your first request:</p><ol><li><p><strong>A Web3 Wallet:</strong> Web3 wallets are required for not only storing your tokens, but also for deploying your smart contracts and signing messages. Examples include Ledger, Trezor, MetaMask, Coinbase Wallet, or Trust Wallet.</p></li><li><p><strong>An IDE:</strong> EVM-compatible Integrated development environments (IDE) like <a href="https://remix.ethereum.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Remix</a> are required for deploying and testing your smart contract. Advanced users may prefer Hardhat or Foundry, particularly for more complex deployments.</p></li><li><p><strong>Solidity:</strong> Solidity is Ethereum's primary programming language for developing smart contracts. It will be helpful to have at least a basic understanding of Solidity before getting started.</p></li></ol><p>An additional crucial element that you'll need is a well-defined use case. What project are you working on? What specific on-chain data and APIs are integral to your objectives? And perhaps most importantly, what is your plan for utilizing the data once it's retrieved? The possibilities are endless, and the only true constraint here is the extent of your imagination.</p><p>If you don't already have a well-defined use case, here are a few custom data feed ideas:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Weather Data:</strong> Retrieve daily and hourly weather forecasts, current conditions, and daily index data from data providers such as OpenWeather or AccuWeather.</p></li><li><p><strong>Sports Data:</strong> Retrieve live scores, player statistics, team information, and historical data from virtually any sports team from data providers include TheRundown or SportsDataIO.</p></li><li><p><strong>DeFi Data:</strong> Real-time and historical cryptocurrency price data, market analysis, and other vital metrics across a multitude of exchanges from data providers such as CryptoCompare.</p></li><li><p><strong>Real-World Asset Data:</strong> Physical and traditional assets such as cash, commodities, equities, bonds, credit, artwork, and intellectual property from professional data providers (e.g. Kelly Blue Book for cars), independent/expert appraisers, exchanges/OTC markets, or any customized aggregation of data sources.</p></li><li><p><strong>IoT Data:</strong> Supply chain tracking, accounting transparency, health wearables, consumption and pollution, parametric insurance that tracks rainfall, GPS sensors, and more.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Chainlink oracles can return data from anywhere on the internet.</strong> For more ideas, we recommend looking into Chainlink's blog on the <a href="https://blog.chain.link/smart-contract-use-cases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">77 different use cases enabled by Chainlink</a>. Additional custom data feed examples that walk you through building a custom data feed can be found within our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Any-API-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website's documentation</a>.</p><blockquote><p><em>If you are interested in the actual mechanics of how requests to Chainlink nodes operate under the hood, feel free to check out our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/Direct-Request-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">direct request guide</a>.</em></p></blockquote><p>Without further ado, here are the 7 steps for requesting a custom Chainlink data feed.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-1-finding-a-suitable-chainlink-node-operator"><strong>Step 1:</strong> Finding a Suitable Chainlink Node Operator<a href="#step-1-finding-a-suitable-chainlink-node-operator" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to step-1-finding-a-suitable-chainlink-node-operator" title="Direct link to step-1-finding-a-suitable-chainlink-node-operator">​</a></h3><p>This is arguably the most crucial step of all. Similar to the way a highly-skilled CPA can enhance tax strategization, potentially leading to substantial annual savings, the importance of proficient Chainlink node operators cannot be overstated.</p><p>Working with a knowledgeable and competent Chainlink node operator can greatly streamline the process of requesting and building a custom data feed, allowing you or your team to allocate resources more efficiently to your Web3 application. Furthermore, these node operators should possess the expertise to assist in crafting your smart contract code, conducting code reviews, and suggesting gas optimization strategies within your smart contract. This not only saves time, but can also preserve valuable funds with each data request to the Chainlink oracle.</p><p>Here's what you should look for when it comes to a Chainlink node operator:</p><ol><li><p>Trustworthy and reliable.</p></li><li><p>A proven track record.</p></li><li><p>Strong communication skills.</p></li><li><p>Transparent and clearly-defined pricing.</p></li><li><p>Reliable, secure, and redundant infrastructure.</p></li><li><p>Knowledgeable in Solidity.</p></li><li><p>A well-defined process for requesting custom data feeds.</p></li><li><p>Continuous monitoring of each data feed request pipeline.</p></li><li><p>A clear service-level agreement (SLA) for their data feed performance.</p></li></ol><blockquote><p><em>At LinkWell Nodes, we do our best to align with these characteristics and qualities.</em>
<em>Our services include <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions</a> across 14 mainnet and 13 testnet blockchains. Beyond that, our suite of <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/Development-Services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">development services</a> is designed to cater to the diverse needs of your Web3 project. We also offer robust documentation on our website in order to help facilitate this process.</em></p></blockquote><p><strong>Where Can I Find a Chainlink Oracle?</strong></p><p>As of the time of writing, there lacks a centralized marketplace for Chainlink oracles. Historically, a Chainlink node marketplace existed at market.link. However, market.link has been deprecated, and the primary avenue for finding an oracle is by sending a chat within the <strong>#operator-requests</strong> channel of the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/chainlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Official Discord server</a>. Additionally, a simple Google search can yield information about the various Chainlink node operators and the services they publicly offer.</p><p>Ultimately, the responsibility lies with you to diligently vet and select a Chainlink node operator who aligns with the characteristics specified above.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-2-communicating-your-data-requests"><strong>Step 2: Communicating Your Data Requests</strong><a href="#step-2-communicating-your-data-requests" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to step-2-communicating-your-data-requests" title="Direct link to step-2-communicating-your-data-requests">​</a></h3><p>After selecting a Chainlink node operator, you'll want to succinctly convey to them the requirements of your Web3 project. It is beneficial to provide the following information to facilitate effective collaboration:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Blockchain Network:</strong> The blockchain network you plan on deploying your application on.</p></li><li><p><strong>Data Type:</strong> The type of data you are requesting (i.e., uint256, string[], bool, etc.).</p></li><li><p><strong>Frequency:</strong> The expected frequency of the request to the oracle (i.e. once a day, once a minute, etc.).</p></li><li><p><strong>External Adapter:</strong> External adapters exist to perform a variety of custom logic against diverse range of off-chain resources. These resources encompass premium data providers, authenticated web APIs, IoT sensors, bank payments, enterprise back-ends, other blockchain networks, and various other sources.</p></li><li><p><strong>Urgency:</strong> How soon do you need your new data feed up &amp; running?</p></li><li><p><strong>Decentralization requirements:</strong> Would you find it acceptable to have one Chainlink node operations team managing your data feed using multiple redundant Chainlink nodes, or do you specifically require the involvement of multiple node operator teams?</p></li><li><p><strong>Other Chainlink Services:</strong> Do you require additional Chainlink services such as <a href="https://docs.chain.link/chainlink-automation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Automation</a> or <a href="https://docs.chain.link/vrf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VRF</a> to be implemented within your smart contract?</p></li><li><p><strong>API endpoint:</strong> What HTTP URL do you need to request data from? Does it require an API key, a request body, or any headers? Sending a sample CURL command to the node operator should be sufficient here. Example below:</p></li></ol><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    curl https://myApi.com/BTC/USD --request POST --header "X-Auth-Key: my-api-key-123" --data '{"interval": 1, "count": 10}'</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><blockquote><p><em>At LinkWell Nodes, to simplify the process of requesting a new data feed, we ask that you fill out our specialized <a href="https://linkwellnodes.io/Getting-Started.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">data feed request form</a>. Once we receive your submission, we'll make every effort to respond promptly and provide your custom data feed ASAP (typically within the day).</em></p></blockquote><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-3-building-and-deploying-your-smart-contract">Step 3: Building and Deploying Your Smart Contract<a href="#step-3-building-and-deploying-your-smart-contract" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 3: Building and Deploying Your Smart Contract" title="Direct link to Step 3: Building and Deploying Your Smart Contract">​</a></h3><p>Although you may have already commenced the development of your smart contract before reaching out to a Chainlink node operator, you may need to modify it to suit your chosen oracle's requirements.</p><blockquote><p><em>At LinkWell Nodes, we provide <a href="https://github.com/LinkWellNodes/Documentation/blob/main/docs/services/direct-request-jobs/mainnets/Arbitrum-One/uint256/uint256.sol#L48-L56" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">comprehensive code samples</a> to help you get started on your contract development. These examples serve as a valuable resource in kick-starting your smart contract development, or incorporating our data feeds into your existing smart contract.</em></p></blockquote><p><strong>Key methods within your smart contract include:</strong></p><ol><li><strong>The Constructor:</strong> Here you'll typically specify the <a href="https://docs.chain.link/resources/link-token-contracts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink (LINK) token contract address</a> for your respective chain, the oracle address, the job ID, and the per-request payment amount. Oracle addresses, job IDs, and payment amounts are provided by (or negotiated with) your chosen node operator.</li></ol><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    constructor() ConfirmedOwner(msg.sender) {</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        _setChainlinkToken(0x0Fd9e8d3aF1aaee056EB9e802c3A762a667b1904);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        setOracleAddress(0xd36c6B1777c7f3Db1B3201bDD87081A9045B7b46);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        setJobId("a8356f48569c434eaa4ac5fcb4db5cc0");</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        setFeeInHundredthsOfLink(0);     // 0 LINK</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    }</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><ol start="2"><li><strong>The Request Function:</strong> The request function (also called the transferAndCall() or _sendOperatorRequest() function) defines your request characteristics, and sends the request (and payment) to the Chainlink oracle.</li></ol><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    function request() public {</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        Chainlink.Request memory req = _buildOperatorRequest(jobId, this.fulfill.selector);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        // DEFINE THE REQUEST PARAMETERS (example)</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._add('method', 'GET');</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._add('url', 'https://min-api.cryptocompare.com/data/pricemulti?fsyms=BTC,ETH&amp;tsyms=USD,EUR');</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._add('headers', '["content-type", "application/json", "set-cookie", "sid=14A52"]');</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._add('body', '');</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._add('contact', '');     // PLEASE ENTER YOUR CONTACT INFO. this allows us to notify you in the event of any emergencies related to your request (ie, bugs, downtime, etc.). example values: 'derek_linkwellnodes.io' (Discord handle) OR 'derek@linkwellnodes.io' OR '+1-617-545-4721'</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        // The following curl command simulates the above request parameters: </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        // curl 'https://min-api.cryptocompare.com/data/pricemulti?fsyms=BTC,ETH&amp;tsyms=USD,EUR' --request 'GET' --header 'content-type: application/json' --header 'set-cookie: sid=14A52'</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        // PROCESS THE RESULT (example)</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._add('path', 'ETH,USD');</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        req._addInt('multiplier', 10 ** 18);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        // Send the request to the Chainlink oracle        </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        _sendOperatorRequest(req, fee);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    }</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><blockquote><p><em>LinkWell Nodes implements a unique and innovative approach that allows for greater control over building your request, but requires a few additional parameters be set (as in the above example).
<strong>Please refer to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a> when building your request - especially in regards to these required request parameters.</strong> </em></p></blockquote><ol start="3"><li><strong>The Fulfill Function:</strong> Once the data has been retrieved, parsed, and converted into a blockchain-compatible format, our oracle node executes a blockchain transaction against the oracle contract, which in turn writes the data back to your consumer contract via execution of your fulfill() function.</li></ol><div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    uint256 public response;</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    // Receive the result from the Chainlink oracle    </span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    event RequestFulfilled(bytes32 indexed requestId);</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    function fulfill(bytes32 requestId, uint256 data) public recordChainlinkFulfillment(requestId) {</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">     // Process the oracle response</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        // emit RequestFulfilled(requestId);    // (optional) emits this event in the on-chain transaction logs, allowing Web3 applications to listen for this transaction</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">        response = data;     // example value: 1875870000000000000000 (1875.87 before "multiplier" is applied)</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    }</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p><strong>Now, deploy it!</strong></p><p>Now that your smart contract's been drafted up, it's time to deploy it. We suggest deploying your smart contract onto a testnet initially, so that you can validate your request logic in a low-risk environment before deploying onto a mainnet. If you need guidance during this process, you can refer to a brief <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vH8T3In6ZkE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube tutorial on Remix</a> by EatTheBlocks. We are happy to assist as well!</p><blockquote><p><em>LinkWell Nodes offers free Chainlink oracle requests on all blockchain testnets, as part of our dedication to supporting the Chainlink community and assisting new Web3 developers.
We encourage Web3 developers to <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/testnets" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">take advantage</a> of this opportunity to submit their requests without any cost.</em></p></blockquote><center><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vH8T3In6ZkE" frameborder="0"></iframe></center><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-4-testing-the-chainlink-oracle-request-in-your-smart-contract">Step 4: Testing the Chainlink Oracle Request In Your Smart Contract<a href="#step-4-testing-the-chainlink-oracle-request-in-your-smart-contract" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 4: Testing the Chainlink Oracle Request In Your Smart Contract" title="Direct link to Step 4: Testing the Chainlink Oracle Request In Your Smart Contract">​</a></h3><p>Now comes the fun part - executing the request logic against the oracle specified in your constructor method.</p><p>Your first step is to deploy your smart contract code using the <a href="https://remix.ethereum.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Remix IDE</a>. After deploying the contract, the next step is to trigger the transferAndCall() function (sometimes called the request() or _sendOperatorRequest() function, highlighted in purple below) within your consumer contract.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Remix Figure 1" src="/assets/images/Remix_Diagram_1-d47668fbf53b510a9c6ea8d392e38701.webp" width="1788" height="856" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Once your data has successfully been retrieved and parsed, our oracle node executes a blockchain transaction against the oracle contract, which in turn writes the data back to your consumer contract via its fulfill() function. Receiving your response may take up to 60 seconds - depending on your chosen blockchain's block time.</p><p>Clicking the response button highlighted in purple below should return the data from your request.</p><blockquote><p><em>If your contract hasn't received a response after waiting 2 minutes, you may have an issue with your request, response, or API endpoint. Please check out our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/faq/Chainlink-Users#im-not-getting-a-response-back-to-my-consumer-contract" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FAQ</a> on this subject for more troubleshooting information. We also welcome Web3 developers to join our <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord channel</a>, where we are happy to work through any problems that may arise.</em></p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Remix Diagram 2" src="/assets/images/Remix_Diagram_2-02cce566df7ef13d31f84e093c19b056.webp" width="1788" height="856" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Once the data has been returned, you are free to utilize that data within your smart contract for whatever purpose you need.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-5-optimizing-your-smart-contracts-request-and-fulfill-functions-optional">Step 5: Optimizing Your Smart Contract's Request and Fulfill Functions (Optional)<a href="#step-5-optimizing-your-smart-contracts-request-and-fulfill-functions-optional" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 5: Optimizing Your Smart Contract's Request and Fulfill Functions (Optional)" title="Direct link to Step 5: Optimizing Your Smart Contract's Request and Fulfill Functions (Optional)">​</a></h3><p>This step is marked as optional, as it is geared towards advanced users and/or use cases.</p><p>Reducing the gas costs incurred by the Chainlink node operator in writing your result to your smart contract generally lowers the LINK they'll need to charge you per request. Therefore, it is typically advisable to optimize your fulfill() function's gas usage, in order to increase the overall cost-effectiveness of your Chainlink requests.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Side note</strong>: <em>If your transaction is failing due to an 'out of gas' error, you have several options: A) Provide a smaller response, B) Divide your request into multiple oracle transactions, or C) Reach out to the relevant oracle team to request an increased gas allowance for your specific use case (which may lead to higher job pricing).</em></p></blockquote><p>As previously mentioned, optimizing your smart contract's request and fulfill functions is a service we offer as part of our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/Development-Services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">development services</a>.</p><p>One other key point - gas prices can be unpredictable, especially when deploying your application on the Ethereum network. In the event of a significant surge in gas prices, the costs incurred by the node operator will spike as well. This forces many node operators to price their data feeds at higher rate to balance out the losses incurred by these market spikes. Consulting with your node operator beforehand on their pricing model may lead to informative conversations here. Whenever possible, we strongly recommend deploying your Web3 application on a layer 2 network such as Arbitrum or Optimism.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-6-deploying-your-smart-contract-on-mainnet-and-validating-the-request-and-fulfill-functions">Step 6: Deploying Your Smart Contract On Mainnet and Validating the Request and Fulfill Functions<a href="#step-6-deploying-your-smart-contract-on-mainnet-and-validating-the-request-and-fulfill-functions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 6: Deploying Your Smart Contract On Mainnet and Validating the Request and Fulfill Functions" title="Direct link to Step 6: Deploying Your Smart Contract On Mainnet and Validating the Request and Fulfill Functions">​</a></h3><p>In this step, we'll discuss the deployment of your smart contract to a mainnet vs a testnet blockchain network.</p><p>One notable difference when transitioning from a testnet oracle request to a mainnet oracle request is that your mainnet requests that you send require a nominal fee in the form of the LINK token (usually around 0.1 LINK, depending on the blockchain network and data type). For this reason, it is necessary to fund your smart contract with LINK in order to accommodate the anticipated request volume for your Web3 application.</p><p>After deploying and funding your mainnet contract, we suggest executing your request function at least once to ensure your functionality is working as expected.</p><blockquote><p><em>At LinkWell Nodes, we strive for transparency and efficiency around our pricing model. For a more comprehensive understanding of the factors that influence our data feed pricing, you can explore our pricing article <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.
<strong>Our commitment is to offer the most competitive pricing in the market.</strong> Deploying your contract initially onto a testnet and making a few requests to our oracles can help us significantly in gauging the lowest-possible pricing for your custom data feed.</em></p></blockquote><h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="step-7-go-live-with-your-web3-application"><strong>Step 7: Go Live With Your Web3 Application</strong><a href="#step-7-go-live-with-your-web3-application" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to step-7-go-live-with-your-web3-application" title="Direct link to step-7-go-live-with-your-web3-application">​</a></h3><p>Congratulations on reaching this point!</p><p>Now that your application's data pipeline is fully deployed, you'll need to find some users to interact with your newly-minted and Chainlink-secured Web3 application.</p><p>Here are some final recommendations for your Chainlink integration:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Implement Other Chainlink Services:</strong> Your smart contract development journey doesn't need to end with custom data feeds. Chainlink offers a diverse array of supplementary services that can further elevate the potential of your projects. Chainlink Automation, for example, can be an enhancement for automating the request() function to your custom data feed.</p></li><li><p><strong>Communication:</strong> Practice keeping an open line of communication with your chosen Chainlink node operator to ensure a rapid response in the event of any issues, downtime, or changes you might like them to make.</p></li><li><p><strong>Monitoring:</strong> Ensure that your selected Chainlink node operator consistently monitors the request pipeline of your custom data feed. To this end, ask them what their alerting policy is for their mainnet data feeds (if any). This vigilance helps to keep your Web3 application safe in the event of any integration issues, such as your API endpoint failing to respond to your oracle's requests.</p><blockquote><p><em>At LinkWell Nodes, it is our mission to provide transparency, security, and ownership over all of your data delivery needs. To that end, we provide a clear <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Service-Level-Agreement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service-Level Agreement (SLA)</a> for all of our mainnet data feeds.</em></p></blockquote></li></ol><p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p><p>With the proper knowledge and understanding in place, navigating the process of requesting, building, and integrating a Chainlink data feed should not only be seamless - it should be fun and exciting as well! We sincerely hope that this guide serves as a solid foundation for Web3 teams looking to integrate Chainlink's powerful Web3 services and capabilities into their smart contracts.</p><p><strong>Looking for a way to get involved?</strong> Join a team and participate in a hackathon hosted by Chainlink. Hackathons are a great opportunity to enhance your Web3 knowledge, network among like-minded Web3 professionals, meet industry leaders, and even win some cool prizes!</p><hr><blockquote><p><em>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink oracle.</em></p><p><em>We provide custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions across all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.</em></p><p><em>Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a></em>, <em>or hop into our <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a> and ask for help!</em></p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" src="/assets/images/lw-banner_1080x606-c6d84e1ae6e43af8c26ee04d238969be.webp" title="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" width="1080" height="606" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="chainlink" term="chainlink"/>
        <category label="oracle" term="oracle"/>
        <category label="smart contract" term="smart contract"/>
        <category label="web3" term="web3"/>
        <category label="blockchain" term="blockchain"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chainlink Any API - Direct Request vs. Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Chainlink-Any-API-Direct-Requests-Vs-Functions</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Chainlink-Any-API-Direct-Requests-Vs-Functions"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the pros and cons of Chainlink's Direct Requests vs. Functions - A guide for Web3 developers for off-chain data retrieval and computation.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Chainlink Any API - Direct Request vs. Functions" src="/assets/images/Header-5dd6c65d31fe89a1a655ace10c4d70b2.webp" title="Chainlink Any API - Direct Request vs. Functions" width="1400" height="788" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Direct Requests vs. Functions: How to decide?</strong></p><p>Navigating the ever-evolving landscape of Chainlink and its integrations within the Web3 ecosystem can at times be daunting.</p><p>Since its inception, Chainlink has evolved at a rapid rate. One of the original services provided by Chainlink's decentralized oracle network was <a href="https://docs.chain.link/any-api/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Direct Request jobs</a> (also known as "Any API") — Chainlink's first iteration of a solution to help bridge the gap between on-chain and off-chain data. While it worked effectively, there were inherent shortcomings that eventually prompted the release of <a href="https://docs.chain.link/chainlink-functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Functions</a>, marking an improvement in security, reliability, and self-service capabilities.</p><p>Yet, after the release of Functions, a lingering question remains:</p><p><strong>Are Direct Requests still viable?</strong></p><p>We would argue that they are. </p><p>Make no mistake: Chainlink Functions is a monumental enhancement for off-chain computation and data retrieval, and we believe that Web3 teams should consider using Functions if and when applicable.</p><blockquote><p><em>Disclaimer: All views below are strictly our own, and not the views or opinions of Chainlink Labs. As a community-based Chainlink node operations team with extensive <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Direct Request service offerings</a>, we acknowledge our potential bias in writing on this topic. In that vein, we promise to be as objective as possible in assessing the relevance of both approaches.</em></p></blockquote><p>While Chainlink Functions reigns supreme in many ways to the traditional Direct Request model, there are pros and cons to each approach. Having a nuanced understanding acknowledges the fact that Direct Requests can still be a relevant option for off-chain data data retrieval and computation, depending on your use case.</p><p>Our objective here is to illuminate this choice for Web3 developers, who might be faced with the challenge of selecting one over the other.</p><p><strong>Let's begin by examining Chainlink Direct Requests (Any API):</strong></p><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ay4rXZhAefs?si=Rat05_PI4LfNU1dJ" title="Requesting data from a Chainlink oracle using Any API (Direct) Requests" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe><p>Direct Requests are the first iteration of Chainlink's service offerings that allow Web3 teams to write off-chain data (ie, data from the internet) to the blockchain. With their initial release, Direct Requests enabled a wide array of use cases across many industries ranging from finance, to insurance, to NFTs, and more.</p><p>More specifically, Direct Requests allow for a smart contract developer to make ad-hoc requests to an existing Chainlink node (oracle), which in turn responds by writing the requested value(s) back to the requestor's smart contract. In short, Direct Requests allow smart contracts to request data from the internet in a secure way.</p><p>While our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/Direct-Request-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a> elaborates much more extensively on the mechanics of Direct Request jobs, here's a high-level overview:</p><ol><li>A smart contract (i.e., ChainlinkClient) — also known as a 'consumer contract' — makes a request to an on-chain oracle contract, typically owned and operated by a Chainlink node operator.</li><li>The relevant Chainlink node receives the request, interacts with the relevant API endpoint via HTTP, and writes the requested data back to the consumer contract.</li><li>The Web3 application reads the data from the consumer contract and executes the desired business logic based on this data.</li></ol><p>The following diagram illustrates a direct request to a Chainlink node via the manual triggering of the smart contract's request function. This request may be triggered via MetaMask, Chainlink Automation, web3.js call to an RPC endpoint, or any other means.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Chainlink Direct Request Diagram" src="/assets/images/Chainlink-Direct-Request-Diagram-f3c468e603515c2b1416a979af9d8d8a.webp" title="Chainlink Direct Request Diagram" width="896" height="666" class="img_ev3q"></p><center><strong>Figure 1</strong>: Chainlink Direct Request Model</center><p></p><p>Until recently, Direct Requests were the only viable solution for Web3 developers looking to securely write external data on-chain. Since its inception, Direct Requests have successfully been implemented by hundreds of teams within the <a href="https://www.chainlinkecosystem.com/ecosystem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Ecosystem</a>.</p><p>And yet — inherent shortcomings within the Direct Request model have precipitated the emergence of Chainlink Functions.</p><p><strong>Shortcomings of the Direct Request model:</strong></p><ol><li><strong>Searching for a Suitable Chainlink Node Operator</strong>- To make a direct request, Web3 developers must first find a suitable node operator via <a href="https://discord.com/invite/chainlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink's official Discord server</a> (#operator-requests channel).</li><li><strong>Reliability Concerns</strong> — Within distributed and decentralized systems, single points of failure (SPOFs) are not ideal. Selecting a single Chainlink node operator — especially one not well-versed in an elastic, redundant infrastructure design- can lead to availability and reliability concerns.</li><li><strong>Centralization Risks</strong> — Entrusting data to a single Chainlink node operator poses trust issues, wherein a nefarious node operator could potentially manipulate data before writing it on-chain.</li><li><strong>External Adapters</strong> — Direct Requests must offload any advanced logic (ie, complicated parsing or post-processing of data) to an external adapter (EA) — a small, server-side runtime that hosts such functionality. Some oracles (such as us!) offer this service for free, whereas others require you to write or provide your own external adapter.</li></ol><p>As a result of these drawbacks, some Web3 developers have resorted to running their own Chainlink node in order to mitigate security and trust concerns. Yet, running a production-grade Chainlink infrastructure demands <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/faq/Chainlink-Operators#profitability" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">substantial effort</a>, diverting valuable resources (both financial and otherwise) that could otherwise be spent on application development.</p><blockquote><p><em>&nbsp;<strong>A short plug</strong>: At LinkWell Nodes, we offer a robust suite of Direct Request service offerings that mitigates many of the above shortcomings. By following our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Direct Request API documentation</a>, you'll be able to develop a self-service Any API solution, and be up and running in minutes.</em></p><p><em>We also offer a comprehensive list of free service offerings to all customers, including free external adapter development, hosting, <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Service-Level-Agreement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">data security guarantee</a>, and 24/7 monitoring of your direct request infrastructure.</em></p></blockquote><hr><p><strong>Enter Chainlink Functions.</strong></p><p>As a result of the historic challenges with Direct Requests, <a href="https://docs.chain.link/chainlink-functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink Functions</a> emerged as a decentralized, self-service alternative in March 2023. Chainlink Functions executes all request logic on a DON (Decentralized Oracle Network), instead of via a single Chainlink Oracle — thereby minimizing concerns around centralization and reliability.</p><p>It's worth mentioning that Chainlink Functions operates via a self-service request model: users write their request functionality in JavaScript (JS), and a network of node operators executes the logic and returns the response.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Chainlink Functions" src="/assets/images/Chainlink-Functions-Diagram-96f2645ec08a48d3441f64be35b67156.webp" width="2048" height="877" class="img_ev3q"></p><center><strong>Figure 2</strong>: Chainlink Functions request model</center><p></p><p>From <a href="https://blog.chain.link/introducing-chainlink-functions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink's blog</a>, major benefits of Functions include:</p><ul><li><strong>Trust-minimized security:</strong> Build upon time-tested decentralized infrastructure that already helps secure billions of dollars for Web3 apps.</li><li><strong>Self-service model:</strong> Get started in minutes with Functions' serverless development solution, which features a CLI, starter kits, and a debugging environment.</li><li><strong>Serverless runtime environment:</strong> Run JavaScript (JS) code in a serverless manner so that you can focus less on infrastructure (ie, writing an external adapter), and more on your core application.</li></ul><p>The accessibility brought by Functions fundamentally transforms the landscape for Web3 developers, opening boundless opportunities for smart contracts to interact with the real world in a trust-minimized manner.</p><p><strong>Drawbacks of Chainlink Functions:</strong></p><p>Despite the obvious benefits and allure of Chainlink Functions, certain <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/faq/Chainlink-Users#limitations-of-chainlink-functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">limitations</a> do need consideration:</p><ol><li><strong>Limited Beta:</strong> Functions is currently in limited Beta. Chainlink's documentation currently states that "developers must follow best practices and not use the Beta for any mission-critical application or secure any value". Furthermore, Functions is only live on four mainnets at the time of this writing — Ethereum, Polygon, Arbitrum, and Avalanche (you can check the most up-to-date list of networks here).</li><li><strong>Service Limits:</strong> Functions imposes several service limitations (ie, gas cost, execution time, and idempotence of your business logic) which you can view within <a href="https://docs.chain.link/chainlink-functions/resources/service-limits" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink's documentation</a>.</li><li><strong>Must program your own request in JavaScript (JS):</strong> Lastly, in order to use Chainlink Functions, you'll need to write your own request and response logic using JavaScript (JS). This may be a limitation for some users.</li></ol><p>While Chainlink Functions will almost certainly continue to evolve, the current state of the above limitations may give some users pause for production Web3 applications.</p><p>In the mean time, if you are a Web3 developer or project with time-sensitive requirements for off-chain data and/or computation for your mainnet applications, but are concerned about the above limitations, you ultimately have three options: 1) Wait for Functions to evolve and mature more to support your use case, 2) Implement Functions as-is, or 3) Utilize the Direct Request model (ie, reach out to an existing node operator, such as <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ourselves</a>).</p><p><strong>Pros of Chainlink Direct Requests:</strong></p><p>Given some of the above limitations of Functions, the advantages of Chainlink's Direct Request model for some use cases becomes a bit more clear:</p><ol><li><strong>Maturity:</strong> Direct Requests have a longer-standing track record and established familiarity among developers. This maturity may simplify integration for some users — especially ones with projects that have already implemented the Direct Request logic within their systems.</li><li><strong>Control and Customization:</strong> While Functions provides streamlined and efficient execution, it may not accommodate the specific needs of certain applications which may exceed Function's service limitations (ie, gas costs, network support, execution time, etc.).</li><li><strong>Mainnet Support:</strong> Direct Requests are supported across all mainnet chains that <a href="https://docs.chain.link/resources/link-token-contracts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chainlink supports</a>.</li><li><strong>Pricing:</strong> There is also typically a good deal of wiggle room in how much LINK is charged for each Direct Request job, whereas Functions uses a fixed calculation. Additionally, experienced Chainlink node operators can even help out with gas optimization within the client/consumer contracts request and fulfill functions, ultimately enabling them to reduce the amount of LINK charged per request.</li><li><strong>Human Support:</strong> While power users may not require it, establishing a relationship with an existing node operator via the Direct Request model provides for an experienced human component, and a support team that's available when you need the help.</li></ol><hr><p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p><p>The debate between Chainlink's Direct Requests and the innovative Chainlink Functions capabilities reflects the dynamic evolution within Web3, and more specifically, Chainlink's journey to becoming the industry-standard Web3 oracle platform.</p><p>While Chainlink Functions introduces a new realm of efficiency and security within the Chainlink ecosystem for Web3 developers, there are several limitations that warrant consideration. Conversely, while Direct Requests may offer benefits in terms of hands-free implementation, available networks, and pricing, one must consider centralization and reliability risks when making their decision. It's clear that each approach offers distinct advantages and limitations — choosing one will require careful consideration based on the specific needs of your project.</p><p>As the Web3 ecosystem continues to evolve, a nuanced understanding of these approaches will help to empower Web3 developers to navigate the complexities of off-chain data retrieval and computation, and implement the best solution for their endeavors.</p><p>If you have any questions, please don't hesitate to reach out!</p><blockquote><p><em>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink oracle.</em></p><p><em>We provide custom data feed capabilities and self-service oracle solutions across all major mainnet and testnet blockchains supported by Chainlink.</em></p><p><em>Looking for a custom data feed? Head on over to our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">documentation</a></em>, <em>or hop into our <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Xs6SjqVPUA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a> and ask for help!</em></p></blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" src="/assets/images/lw-banner_1080x606-c6d84e1ae6e43af8c26ee04d238969be.webp" title="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" width="1080" height="606" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="chainlink" term="chainlink"/>
        <category label="oracle" term="oracle"/>
        <category label="data" term="data"/>
        <category label="functions" term="functions"/>
        <category label="any api" term="any api"/>
        <category label="web3" term="web3"/>
        <category label="blockchain" term="blockchain"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Introduction</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Introduction"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink oracle. Our mission is to support Web3 developers in building a world powered by cryptographic truth.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LinkWell Nodes is a U.S.-based Chainlink oracle. Our mission is to support Web3 developers in building a world powered by cryptographic truth.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" src="/assets/images/lw-banner_1080x485_Docs-Home-06a666d421b6cdc713b6eb8ce0b6a12f.webp" title="LinkWell Nodes - U.S.-based Chainlink node operator" width="1080" height="485" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It's hard to believe how far Chainlink has come in the span of just five years. From their first white paper in 2017 in which Chainlink proposed a solution to the oracle problem, a problem once thought unsolvable, but refers to the inherent inability of blockchains to access external data, to their recent announcement on their collaboration with SWIFT and 12+ financial institutions, Chainlink has slowly but surely been fulfilling their destiny of becoming a global standard.</p><p>From the start, Chainlink has kept their nose to the grindstone, caring little for media attention or community hype for the first several years, and instead focusing their efforts on researching, developing and building. Last year's SmartCon felt like an inflection point for Chainlink after former Google CEO Eric Schmidt's Fireside chat with Chainlink CEO Sergey Nazarov in which Eric pressured Sergey to just come out and announce Chainlink's true plan - for Chainlink to have a presence in virtually every aspect of Web3.</p><p>And after enabling $7 trillion in transaction value, integrating with over 1,700 Web3 projects and the development of CCIP (which is launching soon), it's safe to say that their plan for total world domination (just kidding, kind of) has slowly but surely been coming to fruition.</p><p>At LinkWell Nodes, we liken ourselves to Chainlink in a sense. While perhaps not on such a large or epic scale, we too have been keeping our nose to the grindstone, researching, developing and building. And after over a year of hard work and dedication building out our Chainlink node infrastructure, we decided it was time to step out of the shadows and formally announce what we've been working on, and what we have in store.</p><p>But before we do, you may be wondering, where did these LinkWell Nodes guys come from? What are they all about, and who are they? Well, hold on to your tendies, as it's time for a short bedtime story.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="our-story">Our Story<a href="#our-story" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Story" title="Direct link to Our Story">​</a></h2><p>LinkWell Nodes' story began shortly after the 2022 Chainlink Oracle Olympics - a global competition of 30 professional teams vying for the right to become the next official Chainlink node operator. As individual participants during the competition, we (Ken and Derek - LinkWell Nodes' co-founders) ended up tying for third place - passing every challenge that Chainlink threw at us, but just barely missing out on the bonus points which cinched the victory for the winning team - NorthWest Nodes.</p><p>Ken likes to blame his wife for being pregnant and giving birth to his second daughter during the last two days of the competition, but all jokes aside, Ken and Derek decided to join forces, and shortly after, LinkWell Nodes was formed.</p><p>As a freshly minted Chainlink node operations team, we immediately went back to the drawing board with an initial vision of designing and engineering the most sophisticated and elegant Chainlink node deployment model that we could possibly devise, with scalability, redundancy, and security at the forefront. With Ken's area of expertise in cybersecurity and Splunk (an enterprise grade monitoring platform), and Derek's area of expertise as a full-stack developer, and our combined expertise with AWS and Chainlink node operations, the path forward was clear.</p><p>After over a year of aggressive engineering efforts in the infrastructure, monitoring, and cybersecurity space with our three favorite technologies - AWS, Splunk, and Chainlink, we think that we were able to succeed in fulfilling that vision.</p><p>Furthermore, we designed our Chainlink infrastructure stack to be easily deployable and reusable, while keeping members of the Chainlink community desiring to spin up their own nodes as quickly and easily as possible, in mind. As a part of our mission to support the Chainlink community, we may be open sourcing some or all of our stack, but more on that later.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="our-mission">Our Mission<a href="#our-mission" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Mission" title="Direct link to Our Mission">​</a></h2><p>Led by truth over trust. Driven to innovate, build and create. Our mission is to support Chainlink in enabling developers, startups and enterprises unlock the true value of Web3.</p><p>Ultimately, we want to help Chainlink fulfill its mission by doing whatever we can to support the Chainlink community. As community-based Chainlink node operators, we are limited to what services we can provide, but that isn't stopping us from going above and beyond the call of duty.</p><p>After spinning up 5 mainnet chains, 6 testnet chains, over 130 direct request jobs and robust documentation to boot, LinkWell Nodes' present objective is to deliver secure, reliable, on-chain data to the general public, all while continuing to innovate on the back-end and supporting the community on the front-end.</p><p>LinkWell Nodes has its eyes set on eventually becoming an official node operator, but more importantly, being recognized as one of the most reliable, communicative, and supportive Node Operator teams present in the Chainlink (and broader Web3) ecosystem.</p><p>While we recognize that Functions, recently released, is a superior method in many ways to the traditional direct request model, it is still in beta, and currently comes with a few limitations. You can check out our FAQ in order to understand our stance on Functions a bit more in-depth, but at this time, we think there is still a desire and need for traditional direct request support.</p><p>That's why we have devoted significant efforts in building out (what we believe) is the most comprehensive set of Chainlink node job offerings and documentation in the public sphere today. Our aim with this effort is to set a new standard for Chainlink community support, and to provide Web3 developers with their off-chain data needs as effortlessly and seamlessly as possible.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="what-we-have-in-store">What We Have In Store<a href="#what-we-have-in-store" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What We Have In Store" title="Direct link to What We Have In Store">​</a></h2><p>Fortunately, we aren't putting all of our eggs in the direct request basket. We've also recognized how challenging it can be for newer Chainlink node operators who don't have as much knowledge or experience as we do with deploying, operating and maintaining Chainlink nodes.</p><p>After noticing the same questions arise over and over again in some of the more popular Chainlink Discord channels, we started building out an FAQ that we hope can act as the start of a knowledge base within our public documentation for both aspiring Chainlink node operators and consumers alike. As an aside, we have our own Discord channel as well if you'd like to pop in and join our small but growing community, or if you are a developer in need of support!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="chainlink-deployment-model-in-aws">Chainlink Deployment Model In AWS<a href="#chainlink-deployment-model-in-aws" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Chainlink Deployment Model In AWS" title="Direct link to Chainlink Deployment Model In AWS">​</a></h2><p>Additionally, as alluded to earlier, we may have plans in place to open source our Chainlink infrastructure stack for other members of the community to use. We aren't providing any guarantees or timelines on a public release at this time, but if there is enough demand and excitement for this release, we will be happy to move forward with it.
To summarize what that release would look like, however, it would be similar to the AWS Quickstart in that after some basic AWS account setup, a new user would simply fill out an AWS Cloudformation template, hit the deploy button, and be up and running with Chainlink node infrastructure in the time it takes to sip your morning coffee.</p><p>One of the major design choices we made with our Chainlink infrastructure deployment model was to make the actual deployment as simple and flexible as possible, with multiple deployment architectures in AWS. Looking to simply spin up a testnet Chainlink node in a public subnet with a 3rd party RPC connection for fast and easy access? We support that.</p><p>What about a highly-available and secure architecture with Chainlink nodes, external adapters and full nodes, and with auto-scaling and load balancing built in? We support that as well across all 5 mainnet chains and 6 testnet chains, all via Infrastructure as Code (IAC), with support for more chains to come in the future. What about monitoring and alerting? Out of the box, we include automatic Cloudwatch monitoring and alerting.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="splunk-integration">Splunk Integration<a href="#splunk-integration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Splunk Integration" title="Direct link to Splunk Integration">​</a></h2><p>But one of the features we are most excited to share is our deep integration with Splunk. While our Splunk integration deserves a separate blog or two on its own (stay posted for that), Splunk is one of the most, if not the most powerful enterprise grade monitoring, alerting and analytics tool on the market today. For the ninth time running, Splunk was named a "Leader" in Gartner's 2022 Magic Quadrant (MQ) for Security Information and Event Management (SIEM).</p><p>Tireless efforts were made to not only automatically deploy and configure Splunk within our Cloudformation templates at the flip of a switch, but to also automatically forward all Chainlink infrastructure logs directly into Splunk upon instance boot, if desired to do so.</p><p>As we were able to engineer this solution from the ground up, the infrastructure logs and metrics coming from Chainlink nodes, databases, full nodes and external adapters, to name some of the major ones, get fired off to Splunk where they are stored, parsed and configured to populate a robust suite of Chainlink monitoring dashboards and alerts that are wrapped up in our custom built Splunk application.</p><p>We didn't just stop at Chainlink infrastructure logs either, as we have monitoring in place at the AWS account level. Cloudtrail API calls, config changes, IAM actions, VPN activity and more are all forwarded and logged in Splunk. And yes, we have dashboards and alerts for this activity too.</p><p>As self-proclaimed trendsetters and innovators with the perfect skill sets and background to bring our Chainlink infrastructure and Splunk monitoring capability to life, we don't mention any of this in a boastful manner, but mostly because we are passionate and excited to share what we've developed, and what we have to offer, with the greater Chainlink community.</p><p>That being said, it's important to note that due to the exhaustive and at times cumbersome nature of configuring and maintaining Splunk, if there were enough interest and demand, we are considering offering Splunk, along with several other very useful of powerful features that we haven't mentioned yet, as a set of premium but optional capabilities under a subscription based model.</p><p>In a perfect world we'd open source everything, but for the time being we aren't quite there yet, so even a small subscription fee would help our ambitious development efforts towards supporting the Chainlink community. But we can cross that bridge when we get there.</p><p>Lastly, we recognize that there will likely be an endless need for Chainlink educators and content creators. Whether that be educational content geared towards Chainlink node operations, or content geared towards supporting Web3 developers interested in using Chainlink services, we are here to help.</p><p>With what feels like a bull market just around the corner coupled with Chainlink's seemingly unstoppable momentum, there couldn't be a more exciting time to be a part of the Chainlink community, and one can't help but wonder what the next 5 years will have in store!</p><p>If you are interested in staying tuned, feel free to join our Discord, or follow us on Twitter @LinkWell_Nodes.</p><p>Thanks for reading!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Derek Ricciuto</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/LinkWellNodes</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Chainlink" term="Chainlink"/>
        <category label="Splunk" term="Splunk"/>
        <category label="AWS" term="AWS"/>
        <category label="oracles" term="oracles"/>
        <category label="web3" term="web3"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Welcome</id>
        <link href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/blog/Welcome"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to our blog!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to our blog!</p><p>At our core, we are committed to supporting the Chainlink community in any way we can. Through our expertise as Chainlink node operators and Web3 developers, we strive to provide useful and actionable content to help users and developers navigate the Chainlink ecosystem. We are dedicated to sharing our knowledge and insights to empower individuals and teams in their journey with Chainlink.</p><p>In this blog, we will cover a wide range of topics that we believe both aspiring Chainlink node operators and Chainlink users (Web3-based developers, projects, or teams) will greatly benefit from. For Chainlink node operators, we will share insights gained from deploying Chainlink nodes over the past few years, as well as our expertise in various industries including cloud, monitoring, security, development, and more.</p><p>The topics we will discuss include deploying Chainlink nodes and the associated infrastructure such as full nodes, external adapters, and databases. We will also address lesser-known subjects such as Chainlink node profitability, who should run a node and why, node maintenance, security, monitoring, and much more.</p><p>With extensive experience supporting Web3 requests for data via Chainlink, we are also committed to peeling back the curtain when it comes to interacting with Chainlink node operators such as ourselves, and also by providing clear and concise documentation for our direct request Any API services. We have already begun this effort with our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Jobs-and-Pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Direct Request Guide</a> and <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/services/direct-request-jobs/Any-API-Guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Any API Examples</a>, and we will continue to cover all of Chainlink's services in future blog posts, including CCIP, VRF, Functions, Automation, Data Feeds, and of course, Any API.</p><p>Additionally, we have encountered numerous recurring questions. These questions include: "Should I run my own node or utilize existing node operator services?", "Is running a Chainlink node worth it or profitable?", "How can I find a node operator for a custom data feed I require?", and more. We understand that finding answers to these questions can be challenging, as many of them may not be addressed in Chainlink's comprehensive community resources and online documentation. Our <a href="https://docs.linkwellnodes.io/knowledgebase/FAQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FAQ</a>, and this blog, aim to provide answers to these questions.</p><p>We are thrilled to share our knowledge and expertise with anyone who interacts with Chainlink nodes in any capacity. We hope that you, as the reader, will find value in this blog. If you do, we kindly ask that you consider sharing it on social media! Additionally, feel free to join our Discord community, where you can learn more about specific topics or simply say hello.</p><p>Thank you for reading, and happy exploring!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ken Reiners</name>
            <uri>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ken-reiners-755806167/</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Derek Ricciuto</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/LinkWellNodes</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Chainlink" term="Chainlink"/>
    </entry>
</feed>